<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Yihui Xie | 谢益辉</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Yihui Xie | 谢益辉</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mean, Variance and Something about Sample</title>
      <link>/en/2013/12/mean-and-variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/12/mean-and-variance/</guid>
      <description>OK，I must clear the concepts of those terms because this is the third time I review my notes.
Description of Data If one wants to descript a collection of data, the Mode, Median and Mean are the first three terms to be learned. They are used to show the whole data in one parameter. And yes, one value is enough and the most important property of a dataset is the center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>探秘公钥与私钥</title>
      <link>/cn/2012/06/cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/2012/06/cipher/</guid>
      <description>最近读了阮一峰关于数字签名的介绍，中间有一个问题一直困扰我：既然公钥与私钥是不同的，那它们又是如何保证可逆的解读明文与密文呢？直接讨论这个问</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, My name is YU Miao and I am currently a Postdoctoral Fellow in Prof. Pawliszyn&amp;rsquo;s group).
My major is Environmental Science so I am a dabbler in many science topics. I have board interests such as cook, photograph, programming&amp;hellip; but they are just hobbies, not special talents. So you know I am a dabbler in life, too.
I am lazy, so I just modified Yihui&amp;rsquo;s pages to show this blog(in fact, I just got the parts which I could figure out the meanings and thanks a lot, Yihui).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>/en/vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/vitae/</guid>
      <description>Miao YU Contact Information  Address  Department of Chemistry University of Waterloo 200 University Avenue West Waterloo, Ontario, Canada, N2L 3G1
 Email  42@yufree.cn
 Pages  Yufree&amp;rsquo;s blog
Research Interest POPs, Environmental Processes, Non-targeted Analysis, CSIA, Data Science
Education Background  2010.08 ~ 2016.06, PhD in Environmental Sciences, Research Center for Eco-Environmental Sciences(RCEES), Chinese Academy of Sciences
 2006.08 ~ 2010.06, Bachelor of Science, School of Environmental Science and Technology, Shandong University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>关于我</title>
      <link>/cn/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/about/</guid>
      <description>枫叶国水卢村办大学博士后一枚，路盲，脸盲并伴有间歇性健忘，各方面都在建设中…… 谢益辉: 之前博客风格从这里抄的 hugo: 当前博客风格从这里选的 学术相关</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>简历</title>
      <link>/cn/vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/vitae/</guid>
      <description>联系信息 地址: Department of Chemistry University of Waterloo 200 University Avenue West Waterloo, Ontario, Canada 邮编: N2L 3G1 联系电话: +1 519-888-4567 ext. 31266 Email: 42@yufree.cn 工作信息 2016.08 至今 加拿大滑铁卢大学 博士后 2014.09-2016.07 美国化学会 初级网络分析师（兼职</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>